字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》上季回顾
Last season, on "The Flash"...
我终于能坦然接受她的死
I'd finally come to grips with her death.
我终于能够放下过去
Finally at the place I can move on.
亨利·艾伦
诺拉·艾伦
我的父亲又被夺走了
My father's taken from me.
我必须让自己平静
I need to find some peace.
不管你要做什么  都行
Whatever you need to do, do it.
你再也杀不了她了
You're not gonna kill her ever again.
-我不会伤害你  -不
- Not gonna hurt you. - No.
你安全了
You're safe.
对于人生我只知道一件事
There's only one thing I know about life.
我知道有些事是偶然发生的
I know some things happen by chance.
就是今天了
Today's the day.
就是今天  跟她说
Today's the day. Talk to her.
她在哪
Where is she?
而有些事情是需要我们去促成的
And some things happen because we make them happen.
好了  说出来
Okay, just do it.
说出来就行
Gonna do it.
都跟她说过无数次了
You've talked to her a million times.
说点好听的
Say something clever.
52频道突发新闻
Channel 52 breaking news.
来自中城的最新消息
The latest from Central City,
竞争者对抗闪电小子
被人们称为竞争者的那个
where the mysterious meta-human criminal,
神秘的超能力者罪犯
known only as the Rival is once again
再一次用他那难以置信的速度恐吓平民
terrorizing the populous with his incredible speed.
需要我们帮忙吗  闪电侠
Need our help, Flash?
不用  等我打败这个蠢蛋  他可能会需要
Nah. When I'm done with this fool, he might.
你要对我的城市怎么样
What have you got against my city?
城市没事
The city's just fine.
是城市里的人需要被教育
It's the people in it who need to be educated.
而且我没有竞争者
And I have no rival!
尤其不是你
Especially not you.
-你还好吗  哥们  -没事  谢谢
- You okay, man? - Yeah, thanks.
这家伙真的烦死我了
That guy's really becoming a pain in my ass.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
你下次会搞定他的  闪电侠
You'll get him next time, Flash.
闪电侠
第三季
第一集
打扰一下
E-excuse me?
不好意思  这是你的吗
Hi, sorry. Is this yours?
我觉得可能是你掉的
I think maybe you dropped it.
刚才就在那
It was just right up there.
我不知道怎么了  不过
I don't know what happened, but--
天呐  是我的  我都不知道掉了
Oh, my gosh, yeah, I didn't even realize I dropped it.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
没事  不用客气
Yeah, yeah, it's okay.
等等  我以前见过你  是吧
Wait, I've--I've seen you before, haven't I?
其实我们是小学同学
We actually went to elementary school together.
你不记得我了吗  第23公立小学
You don't remember me? PS 23?
天呐  是的  我记起来了
Oh, my gosh! Right, yes, I remember!
-加里  对吧  -是巴里
- Gary, right! - Uh, Barry.
-加里  -巴里·艾伦
- Barry. - Barry Allen.
-是的  -没关系
- Right. - It's fine.
-抱歉  抱歉  -没事的
- Sorry, sorry. - No, it's fine.
是的  是的  有一个老师...
Yeah, yeah, no, we had Mr....
-辛克利老师  -是的
- Mr. Hinkley. - Yes.
是的  教数学的  他以前经常
Yeah, for math. Yeah, he used to
这么敲黑板
always hit the chalkboard--
用拳头
With his fist.
然后好多粉笔灰都飘起来了
And all the dust would come flying off.
他看上去就像
He'd look just like--
《史努比》里的乒乓
Pig-Pen from "Peanuts."
是的  很...
Yeah, that's...
没错  你怎么样
Yes. How are you?
我很好
I'm really good.
是的  我是犯罪现场鉴证员
Yeah, I'm, uh, CSI.
我在中城警局工作
I work over at, uh, CCPD.
我爸爸也在那工作
Yeah, um, my-my dad works there, too.
-他是警探  -我时不时见到他
- He's a detective. - Yeah, I see him sometimes.
我不认识他  但是我
I don't really know him, but I, you know,
-看到他经过  -嗯
- see him in passing. - Cool, yeah.
再次谢谢你
Thanks again.
看来你今天是我的英雄
I guess you're my hero today.
很高兴能帮忙
Glad I could be there for you.
要不要一起喝杯咖啡
You know what? Uh, would you wanna get a coffee?
我知道你现在正喝着
I mean, I know you're having a coffee right now.
我是说换个时间
I meant, like, you know, at a different time.
和我一起  不一定非得喝咖啡
With me. Or it doesn't even have to be a coffee.
也可以喝点别的
It could be any kind of beverage,
红酒或啤酒之类的
like a wine or a beer, or--
不是说我想灌醉你
not that I wanna get you drunk.
我们可以喝冰红茶  你喜欢喝冰红茶吗
We-we could get iced tea. Do you like iced tea?
你愿意和我一起喝冰红茶吗
Do-- would you wanna get an iced tea with me?
-好啊  -是吗
- Yes, yes. - Yeah?
是的  我愿意和你一起喝冰红茶
Yes, I would like to get an iced tea with you.
-好的  -巴里·艾伦
- Okay. - Barry Allen,
你知道自己很可爱吗
you're very cute, you know that?
-嗯  -但是
- Yeah, yeah. - Yeah, but, um,
你应该稍微放慢说话的语速
you should try talking just a little bit slower.
速度
Speed...
一直都是我的问题
has always been my problem.
拜拜
See you later.
你怎么样  巴里
What's up, Barry?
今天下午你似乎有点闷闷不乐
You look a little less glum this day's afternoon.
曼德斯队长
Captain Mendez,
我约了一个女生  她答应了
I asked out a girl and she said yes.
这感觉太美好了  对吧
There's no better feeling, is there?
绝对的
No better feeling.
在她说"我愿意"之前都是最美好的
Well, until the day she says, "I do".
在那之前  我们总能想到办法解决的
Yeah, we got a ways to go before that, I think.
很好  在我们调查竞争者的时候
Great, well that'll give you a lot of time to catch me up
你有的是时间赶上我的脚步
on where we are with the Rival.
没有实质性证据
Nothing substantive.
他多次袭击中城警局
He hasn't left any hair or skin samples
但是完全没留下任何头发或是皮肤组织
at any of his attacks on the CCPD.
所以你是说没法确定他的身份
So you're telling me there's no way to ID this guy.
闪电侠拦下他时  我们就能查出他的身份
We'll figure out who he is when The Flash stops him.
那闪电侠最好快点
Well, The Flash better hurry up.
一语双关
Pun intended.
好了
Okay.
对了
All right.
有人看到韦斯特警探了吗
Has anybody seen Detective West?
他好像去了物证室
You know, I think he had to stop by evidence.
其实我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is, actually.
抱歉
Sorry.
队长  我今天能早点走吗
Oh, Captain, is it okay if I leave a little early today?
去和美女约会吗
For your hot date?
不是  我只是约了朋友吃饭
No, I'm, uh, just meeting a friend for dinner.
巴里
Barry!
不要
No!
这次你杀不了她了
You're not gonna kill her this time.
你再也杀不了她了
You're not gonna kill her ever again.
没事了  没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
你安全了
You're safe now. Okay?
晚餐
Dinner.
希望袋子里有扭扭薯条
There better be curly fries in there.
人类三周不吃东西也不会死
Yeah, human beings can go almost three weeks without food
所以如果我是你  我会心存感激一点
so I'd sound a little bit more grateful if I were you.
你不会这样对我的  巴里
Well, you wouldn't do that to me, Barry.
毕竟  你是英雄
After all, you're the hero.
或者你忘了
Or did you forget that?
忙着享受你反转的生活  美好的人生
Too busy leading your reverse "It's a Wonderful Life"?
逆转啊
Reverse, huh?
对你来说挺讽刺的
That's irony for you.
所以  我们要怎么称呼这个
So, uh, what should we call this, uh,
你竭心尽力为我们打造的美丽新世界呢
brave new world that you've whipped up for us?
我想的是...
I was thinking...
闪点
Flashpoint.
这个你不想要了吗
So you don't want this?
也许你找到了办法用这玻璃笼子
You may have figured out a way to dampen my speed
抑制了我的速度  但是我终究会出去
with this glass cage, but I will get out of here
我会毁了你的生活  闪电侠  永不罢休
and I will destroy your life, Flash, one way or the other.
不  你不会
No, you won't.
你永远无法离开这里
You're never getting out of here.
并且  你再也无法伤害任何人了
And you're never gonna hurt anybody ever again.
我把你所夺走的一切都拿回来了
I have everything back that you took from me.
我拿回了所有急速夺走的
I have everything Zoom took.
我终于自由了
I'm finally free.
我回家了
I'm home.
这里不是你的家  巴里
This isn't your home, Barry.
这是个幻影
This is a mirage.
一个会结果我们俩人的虚幻小说
A fiction that will end us both,
除非你让我从这鬼地方出去
unless you let me the hell out of this thing!
你没有在听我说  阁下
you're not listening, Don.
我为什么会想要离开这里
Why would I want to get out of here?
我在这里是完整的
I'm whole, here.
这里甚至有一个闪电侠  我就解放了
There's even a Flash, so I don't have to be.
对了  这个勇猛的年轻极速者是谁啊
Yeah, who is this dashing young speedster, huh?
你知道吗  你在乎吗
Do you know? You even care?
你坐在一旁躲着
While you sit around and hide
像个迷失  寂寞的小男孩时
like a lost, lonely little boy,
让其他人冒着生命危险
letting someone else risk their life
去保护这座城市
to protect the city,
我们共同的敌人正对我们虎视眈眈
our common enemy is coming for us both.
你说的共同敌人是谁
What common enemy is that?
时间
Time.
它已经对你产生了影响
It's already screwing with you
还有你所爱之人也是
and everyone you love.
而且很快的  它也会将我
And pretty soon, it's gonna take me
与你一同毁掉
right down along with you.
你知道吗
You know,
你还真有胆量
you've got some nerve.
我佩服你
I'll give you that.
居然警告我不要扰乱其他人生活
Warning me about messing with other people's lives.
你知道我这么做最主要的原因
You--you know the whole reason I did this
就是你对我生活的所作所为
is because of what you did to my life.
对我的家人
To my family.
对我妈妈
To my mother.
终有一日  很快的  巴里
Yeah, well, one day, soon, Barry,
你会请求我再次杀死她
you'll be begging me to kill her again.
-你能帮我拿一下吗  -行
- Can you hold this for me? - Oh, yeah.
我想跟你说一下  那车会发出响声
Oh, I wanted to tell you, the car's making these noises,
就像是一种叮当的声音
like a--kind of a clanking noise...
-你想来开车吗  -随你了
- Do you wanna drive? - Whatever you want.
-小拳王  -我宝贝儿子来啦
- Hey, slugger. - There's my beautiful boy.
一切都还好吧
Is everything all right?
挺好
Yeah.
一切都棒极了
Everything's great.
-早上好  -早上好  巴里
- Mornin'! - Morning, Barry.
早上好
Mornin'.
看起来不错
Looks good.
你这是怎么了
What is up with you?
为什么这么说
What do you mean?
最近  你每天早上都拥抱我
Lately, you hug me every morning
就好像你好几个月没见过我似的
as if it's the first time you've seen me in months.
那个  如果你想的话  我可以不抱了
Well, I mean, I'll stop if you really want me to.
绝不要  我爱死了
Never. I love it.
巴里  我想要告诉你
Oh, Barry, I wanted to tell you,
几周前 我卖了栋房子
I sold a house to a nice older couple
给一对老夫妇
a few weeks ago.
那房子的地下室公寓
The basement apartment.
他们早上发电邮
They emailed me this morning
告诉我他们想租出去
to tell me they wanted to rent it.
-挺好  -价格很实惠
- Cool. - Very reasonably.
你想让我搬出去吗
You want me to move out?
不不  儿子  别这样  只是
No, no, son, come on. It's just, you know,
如果你有想过约会...
if you ever thought about dating...
我忘了告诉你们
Oh, I forgot to tell you guys.
我在吉特咖啡店
The, uh, the-- the girl that
看到的那个姑娘
I've seen at Jitters--
就是你这3个月一直跟踪的女孩吗
It's the girl you've been stalking for the last three months?
我没有跟踪她
I have not been stalking her.
我在鼓起勇气
I've been working up the courage
-约她出去  -然后呢
- to ask her out. - And?
然后我约了
And I did.
然后她答应了
And she said yes.
太棒了  干得好
All right. Good job.
这姑娘碰到了好男人
This girl just got the best guy, huh?
宝贝
Oh, honey.
中城警署
-好的  -巴仔
- All right. - Hey, Bar.
-怎么了  -看到韦斯特警探了吗
- Yeah? - Have you seen Detective West?
-他  -我告诉过他如果再迟到
- He's-- - I told him that if he was late again,
就可以停职十天了
he'd be facing a ten day RIP.
实际上他昨天提到了什么
Yeah, no, he mentioned something yesterday,
就杰斐逊一案做调查
actually, about running another canvass on that Jefferson case.
这下我明白为什么
Okay. Then I can see why
他一个小时都没接我电话了
he hasn't answered me for the past hour.
也许他身处怪圈什么的
Maybe he's in a weird zone or something.
怪...
A we--
信号区
Cell zone.
韦斯特警探
Detective West?
警...
De--
警探
Detective?
不是吧
Oh, no.
不
No.
乔  你...
Hey, Joe, you got-- -
对不住了  乔
I'm sorry about this, Joe.
怎么...
What the--
下午好  警探
Afternoon, Detective.
-嘿  艾伦  -嘿
- Oh, hey, Allen. - Hey.
我告诉曼德斯队长你又在
So I told Captain Mendez you were canvassing
调查杰斐逊一案
for the Jefferson case again.
薄荷糖要吗
Breath mint?
你为什么
What--why are you talking
和队长提到我
to the Captain about me?
就是你又迟到了
You're just a little late again.
那是我的事  和你无关
That's my business, not yours.
我只是想帮你解围
I was just trying to help you out.
我身上有标着"请帮我"的符号吗
Am I wearing a sign that says "Help me"?
或许应该标个
Might as well be.
就像电影里说的
Look, like they say in the movies,
我们不是搭档  也不是朋友
we're not partners and we're not friends.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
不了解我的生活
You don't know my life,
那为何突然有兴趣帮我保住这破工作
so why the sudden interest in me keeping my lousy job?
我到底哪里那么吸引你了  艾伦先生
And what the hell makes me so interesting to you, Mr. Allen?
告诉我  我真想知道
Tell me. I'd really like to know.
-我  -别忘了
- I--  - And remember,
我正在宿醉中
I have a hangover.
还持着枪
And a gun.
我
I--
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
-什么  -不行
- What? - No.
我不批准
I do not approve.
-嘿  巴里  -嘿
- Hi, Barry. - Hey.
-爸  -爱瑞丝
- Dad. - Iris.
跟我的同事约会你没觉得不妥吗
You think it's a good idea, dating somebody I work with?
只是吃个午饭
It's just a lunch.
其实我都不确定
And truthfully, I wasn't even sure
你还在这工作
you still worked here.
-可以走了吗  -走吧
- You ready? - Yeah, let's do it.
好
Okay.
还好吧
How's it going?
很好  我去拿外套
Good. I just gotta go grab my jacket.
抱歉刚才让你看到
I'm sorry about that mini-scene
-我和我爸顶嘴  -没事
- with my dad, earlier. - Oh, yeah.
没关系的
Don't worry about it.
我只是心疼他
I just feel bad for him.
还有你
And you.
你甚至都不认识我们
You barely even know us.
感觉是老相识
Feels like I do.
很奇怪吗
Is that weird?
我这么说很奇怪吗
Is that a weird thing to say?
不
No.
不  奇怪的是我懂你的意思
No, I mean, strangely, I know what you mean.
我从没答应过像你这种邀约
I never say yes to guys asking me out like that.
可我却答应你了
Yet, I said yes to you.
这是为什么呢
Why'd I do that?
不知道
I don't know.
我猜有些人
Some people are just meant to
注定不会错过
be in your life, I guess.
那说说你的情况吧
So, um, tell me about you.
-好  -父母呢
- Yeah. - Mom and Dad?
健在
Uh, alive and well.
太好了
That's nice.
关系亲吗
You guys close?
亲  很亲
We are, yeah, very.
我  无法想象生命中没有他们
I...couldn't imagine life without them.
他们爱得痴傻入迷
They're like stupid in love.
但愿某天我也有他们这份爱
I hope I have what they have someday.
你还没遇到你的真命天女
You just haven't met the right girl, yet?
是不是
Is that it?
真命天女正是这样
That's the thing about the right girl.
她就在那  静静等待
She's out there, waiting.
只有足够幸运  才能觅得佳人
Just have to be lucky enough to find her.
你打哪里来  巴里·艾伦
Where'd you come from, Barry Allen?
我一直在这  爱瑞丝
I've always been here, Iris.
-你没事吧  -没事  抱歉
- Are you okay? - Uh, sorry, yeah,
我只是在想
that, um-- I was just thinking
一些事然后...
of something and...
不记得了
I lost it.
怎么了
What's going on?
闪电侠和竞争者在维特大楼
Flash and the Rival are going at it
大打出手
in the Werther Building.
所有人得撤离该区域
Everyone needs to evacuate this area.
真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我得走了
I have to go.
真的  怎么了
Really? What--
真的  我有点事得走了
Yeah, yeah. There's something I have to do.
这个  改天再约  可以吗
This--this was-- rain check, okay?
随时都可以
Anytime.
来吧
Come on.
好了  好了  接住了
Yeah, yeah, that's you...
不不不
No, hey, hey, hey! No! No!
还以为接住了呢
Thought I had him.
沃利
Wally?
你这家伙是谁
Who the hell are you?
这就是你的行动基地啊
So this is your base of operations, huh?
对  不然你以为呢  一座堡垒吗
Yeah. What were you expecting? A fortress?
不是  你懂的
No, you know, no.
以为会更安全点
Just something a little more secure.
很难预料谁会
I mean, you never know who's gonna come
穿门进来
walking through that door.
是啊  我刚准备说同样的话
Yeah, I was just about to say the same thing.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
-你在这做什么  -我不是  我
- What are you doing here? - I'm not--I'm--
他在我和竞争者战斗时突然出现
He showed up when I was fighting the Rival,
而且他已经知道我的身份了
and he already knew who I was.
这就是你约我出来的原因吗
Is that why you asked me out?
因为我弟弟是闪电侠吗
Because my brother is The Flash?
不  不  这完全是个巧合
No, no. This is a complete coincidence.
好了  你是怎么知道我的真实身份的
Okay, how'd you know who I was under the mask?
犯罪现场调查
CSI.
你知道的  我只是  把真相拼凑出来
You know, so I just, uh-- put it together.
我不清楚的是你如何获得这种速度的
So what I don't know is how you got your speed.
好了  在我走上正路之前
Oh, okay, so before I went on the straight and narrow,
我曾经以非法飙车为业
I used to drive illegal cars.
我当时为了让引擎能变得更快
I was messing around with a new nitro formula
摆弄出了一个新的氮气加速配方
to get my engine revving faster.
接着有一天晚上  我顶着雷雨天气比赛
Then one night, I'm racing in a thunder storm,
我的车被闪电击中了
my car get struck by lightning.
然后闪电肯定和氮气配方发生了混合反应
And it must have mixed with the formula
因为  轰的一声
because--boom!
我陷入了长达9个月的昏迷
I was in a coma for nine months.
我醒了之后  就成为了现今世上速度最快的人
Then when I woke up, I was the fastest man alive.
闪电侠
The Flash.
-更像是闪电小子  -别那样叫我
- More like Kid Flash. - Don't call me that.
我就那样叫你啊
I call you that.
好了  都别那样叫我好不好
Okay, how about no one calls me that?
那么你是怎么卷入这一切的
So how did you get involved?
我是《中城时报》的记者
I'm a reporter for CCPN.
相比仅仅只是报道城市中
Instead of just reporting on crimes
发生的犯罪行为
that are happening in the city,
我决定付诸一些实际行动
I decided to do something about it.
姐弟打击犯罪小分队
Brother/sister crime-fighting unit.
你父亲知道你俩这事吗
So does your dad know about you two?
你和他一起工作  你觉得呢
You work with the guy. What do you think?
我觉得  我们得阻止竞争者
I think that... we need to stop the Rival.
-是啊  -我们愿意听取各种建议
- Yeah. - We're open to suggestions.
我这几个月以来一直在试图追赶他
I've been trying to run him down for months.
没什么进展  他很快  也许比我还快
No luck. He's fast. Maybe faster than me.
如果你愿意的话  我觉得也许我能帮上忙
Well, if you're willing, I think maybe I could help.
现在只有一个人能帮我们了
There's only one man who can help us now.
西斯科·拉蒙
Cisco Ramon.
拉蒙工业
这里以前不是尖端科研实验室吗
Didn't this used to be S.T.A.R. Labs?
你过去几年到哪逍遥去了
Where have you been the past few years?
四处游历
Running around.
西斯科通过他的科技应用程序独赚了数十亿
Cisco alone made billions with his tech apps.
-买下了这栋楼  -数十亿
- Bought the building. - Billions.
是啊  西斯科·拉蒙是全美首富
Yeah, Cisco Ramon is the richest man in America.
有比乘直升机
Oh! Is there a better way
更好的上班方式了吗
to get to work than by helicopter?
让我来回答  没  有
Let me answer that. Capital N, little O.
十分正确  拉蒙先生  关于逻辑框架项目
Quite right, Mr. Ramon. As for LogicFrame,
这是个相对较小的初创公司
it's a relatively small startup.
初期收益预计在低两位数
The I.P. is expected to be in the low teens.
给他们投2000万
Offer them 20 mil.
宝贝
Babe,
我  有点事情要处理一下
I, um, got some business to attend to,
那么其他事情我们等会再说
so we'll get on that other matter later?
除非我先办了  对吗
Not if I get on it first, huh?
独立女性
Independent woman.
我喜欢  我喜欢
I like it. I like it.
我告诉过你们别再回来了
I told you never to come back here.
我给你做了一套防摩擦战袍
I make you a friction-proof suit
这样你的衣服就不会在两倍音速时爆炸
so your clothes don't explode at mach 2,
而你们则不把我扯进你们的姐弟对抗犯罪战争
and you leave me out of your brother/sister war on crime.
-约定是这样的  -好了  听我说  拉蒙先生
- That was the deal. - Okay, listen to me, Mr. Ramon.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
我相信你在电视上看到竞争者了
I'm sure you've seen the Rival on TV.
他在威胁这座城以证明自己是最快的
He is terrorizing the city to prove that he's the fastest.
我是说  天知道他接下来要做什么
I mean, God only knows what he's gonna do next.
-我们必须阻止他  -好  那就阻止
- We have to stop him. - Okay, so stop him.
听老天指示  玩得开心
Please, go with God, have fun.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
你知道惹到极速者会怎么样吗
You know what happens when you mess with a Speedster?
这样  就会这样
That. That's what happens.
一只震动的手刺透你的胸膛
You get a vibrating hand going right through your ribcage.
我还是免了
No thanks.
我有大钱要挣呢
My money needs me.
慢着  西斯科  你不打算帮我们吗
Wait, Cisco, you're not gonna help us?
这倒是提醒了我  这人是谁
That reminds me. Who the hell is this?
你把陌生人带到我的实验室
You brought some stranger into my lab
还跟他说我帮过闪电侠
and told them I helped The Flash.
-西斯科  -少来
- Cisco. - Uh-uh.
我不认识你  长豆角
I don't know you, string bean.
长豆...
Str--
-拉蒙先生  -什么事
- Mr. Ramon. - Oh, yes?
我知道你是什么样的人
I do know what kind of person you are.
内心深处  你在意去帮助别人
Deep down, you care about helping other people.
好的  继续说
Please, tell me more.
我听过一段故事  你15岁时
I heard a story about how, when you were 15,
你哥哥丹堤欠了一笔赌债
your brother Dante owed a bookie
他还不上欠的钱
and he couldn't pay back what he owed,
于是你把一夏天送披萨挣的钱
so you gave him all the money you earned that summer
给了他  帮他解围
delivering pizzas to help him.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
我有种感觉
I have a feeling that...
我们会成为很棒的队友
we would work really well together as partners.
一起打倒超能力者
Taking down meta-humans together.
这是我们应该做的事
I mean, it's what we're supposed to do.
我们是一个团队
We're a team.
我们是朋友
We're friends.
没事  我没事  我只是...
I'm okay. I'm okay, I just...
我刚刚...
What was I--
我刚刚说到哪了
What was I just saying?
你这是怎么了
What is going on with you?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
我在这都开始怀疑
And here, I was starting to think
你把我给忘了呢
you'd forgotten all about me.
可我确实在遗忘
But I am forgetting.
我出什么事了
What's happening to me?
我还想你什么时候能发觉呢
I was wondering when you'd notice.
仿佛我一想起过去的一段记忆
It's like I'll be thinking of a moment from my past
然后它就...消失了
and then it-- it vanishes.
就找不回来了  为什么
I can't get it back. Why?
闪点悖论  这是副作用
Flashpoint. It's a side effect.
我告诉过你  你不明白自己的行为
See, I told you before. You don't know what you're doing.
你制造的这个新的现实
This new reality you've created
正在不断覆盖我们知晓的那个现实
is starting to overwrite the reality that you and I know.
所以你原来的生活  你的朋友和家人
So your original life-- your friends, your family--
不久之后  都会消逝不见
pretty soon, all of that will just fade away.
那为什么没发生在你身上
Why isn't it happening to you?
不清楚
Not sure.
除非
Unless--
什么
What?
除非什么
你有什么可笑的
What the hell's so funny?
是你的速度
Your speed!
你越使用你的速度
The more you use it,
你的记忆就消失越快
the faster you lose your memories.
不
No.
不会  你在说谎
No, you're lying.
你只是想让我把你放出去
You just want me to let you out of here.
这可永远不会发生
That's never gonna happen.
未来的你  可没这么蠢
The you I know from the future, he's not this stupid.
你很快就会不记得自己是闪电侠了
Pretty soon, you won't even remember that you're The Flash.
那天一旦到来
And when that happens,
这个世界就会变成永恒
this world will become permanent.
时间将会像水泥一样固定住
Time will set like concrete,
没有什么可以再把事情变回原来的样子
and nothing will be able to change it back to the way it was.
这我没意见
That's fine by me.
你知道你得做什么
You know what you have to do.
你得把我带回那一晚
You have to take me back to that night
让我完成我开始的事情
and let me finish what I started.
你去死吧
You go to hell!
你得把我们俩都带回过去
You're taking both of us there!
现在谁是坏人了呢  闪电侠
Now who's the villain, Flash?
现在谁是坏人
Now who's the villain?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
就像我真的在那儿一样
It's like I'm really there.
别这么做
Don't do that!
我告诉过你这样会吓到我
I told you it freaks me out.
不是我干的
It wasn't me.
你是谁
Who are you?
将会帮你阻止竞争者的人
The man who's gonna help you stop the Rival.
巴里
Barry?
好吧  所以
Okay, so...
我能从你一脸的"我不相信你"
I can tell from the "I don't believe you" looks on your faces
看出你不相信我
that you don't believe me.
我们相信你是极速者  但是
We believe you're a speedster,but
你得再解释一下闪点的那一段了
you're gonna have to explain that part about Flashpoint again.
好吧  听着
All right, look.
这已经是我能想到的最简单版本了
This is as simple as I can put it.
我要用一下这块玻璃板  拉蒙先生
I'm gonna use this glass, Mr. Ramon.
-行吗  -啥
- Okay? - What?
想象一下这条线是时间  好吗
Imagine that this line is time, okay?
我回到过去
I went back in time,
阻止了逆闪杀死我妈妈
stopped the Reverse Flash from killing my mom.
而这样做的同时  我创造出了另一条时间线
In doing so, I created an alternate timeline,
在这个全新的存在里你是闪电小子
a whole new existence where you're Kid Flash...
-是闪电侠  -闪电小子
- The Flash. - Kid Flash.
而西斯科是个亿万富翁
And Cisco's a billionaire.
所以你是说另一条时间线里
So you're saying there's a time line out there
我不是亿万富翁
where I'm not rich?
天呐  这一定是宇宙出故障了
Boy, that's a glitch in the universe.
不  我可不信
No, not buying it.
我的人生就是我的人生
Um, my life is my life.
可不是从三个月前开始的  好吗
Didn't just start three months ago, okay?
我一直就是我
I've always been me.
我不知道该怎么告诉你  沃利
I don't know what to tell you, Wally.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
好吧  听着
Okay, look.
就算我们相信你
Even if we did believe you,
为什么你现在告诉我们这个
why are you telling us this now?
因为
Because...
我已经在这儿躲了太久
I've been hiding here for too long.
竞争者必须被阻止
The Rival needs to be stopped.
我得阻止坏人  而
I stop the bad guys. And...
我们能一起打败他
we can all take him down together.
我一个人就能搞定他
I can get him myself.
那你怎么还没打败他
Then why haven't you?
好吧  我可不感兴趣
Well, I'm not interested.
我不知道我得和你们这群怪胎说多少次
I don't know how many times I gotta tell you freaks.
我已经为社会和国家尽了自己的职责
I already did my bit for queen and country.
等一下  我们遗漏了什么
Wait, we're missing something.
等一下  抱歉
Hold on. Excuse me.
你在做什么  别碰那个
What are you doing? Hey, don't touch that.
找到了
Got it.
刚刚发生了什么
What just happened?
别再带陌生人进我的实验室了
Stop bringing strangers into my lab.
这又是谁
Who is this?
她是凯特琳·斯诺博士
This is Dr. Caitlin Snow.
在我的时间线里  她是我们的队友
In my timeline, she's a part of our team.
你是不是...你把她绑架来的吧
Did you -- You just kidnapped this woman.
我没有
No, I didn't--
好吧  我好像是
Well, yeah, I guess, I--
她是个科学家  我们需要她
She's a scientist. We need her.
我不是科学家
I'm not a scientist.
你不是科学家
You're not a scientist?
我是名眼科医生
I'm an ophthalmologist.
给人看眼睛的
An eye doctor?
儿童眼科医生
Pediatric eye doctor.
闹够了吧
And...we're done.
好吧
Okay.
我能单独跟你聊会儿吗
Can I talk to you in private?
行
Yeah. Yeah.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我是不是被绑架了
Have I'v been kidnapped?
我也不清楚
Unclear.
听着  我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我知道这很难相信
I know that this is hard to believe.
不  巴里  问题就在于
No, that's just it, Barry.
我相信你
I do believe you.
真的  你相信我
You...do? You believe me?
我的生活很美好
I have a good life.
我的工作也很好
I have a good job.
我爱我的弟弟
I love my brother.
但是总觉得不对劲
But something has been off.
总觉得少了点什么
Something has been missing.
这种不对劲的感觉在遇见你时
And that feeling that something is not right with my life,
就消失不见了
that went away the moment that I met you.
在你的那个世界里
We're something else to each other
我们的关系很特殊  对吗
where you come from, aren't we?
对
Yes.
是什么
What?
这...
It's...
不知该如何定义
it's escaped definition.
这是爱吧
But it's love?
因为爱就是这样的感觉
Because this is what love feels like.
始于我们相识的第一天
Since the day that I met you.
有发现
We got something.
这位儿童眼科医生的点子不错
Turns out kiddie eye doc here actually had a good idea.
我一直很好奇为什么没人
I have always wondered why no one
把市里的超速摄像头用来
turned the speed cameras in the city
检测近音速的物体
to register near sonic velocities.
我觉得就是个已经完善的预警系统
Seems like a ready-built early warning system.
于是我重新编程了这些摄像头
So I reprogrammed the cameras.
看
Babadook!
竞争者就在这里
There's your rival.
在威廉姆森区的旧锯木厂里
The old sawmill out by Williamson.
好的  你跟着我行动
All right. Follow my lead?
闪电侠不会当人跟班
The Flash doesn't follow anyone.
听他的话吧  沃利
Listen to him, Wally.
他才是闪电侠
He's the Flash.
你知道吗
You know,
你超级适合做激光视力矫正手术
you would be an excellent candidate for Lasik.
你知道怎么侧翼包抄吗
You know how to flank?
我听电影里面经常说这个词
People always say that in the movies.
"侧翼包抄"  真有这回事吗
Is that, like, a thing, "Flanking"?
你在说什么  "侧翼"
What are you talking about "Flank"--
当然有侧翼包抄了
Yes, flanking's a thing.
听着
All right, look.
我向他正面发起进攻
I'm gonna go at him head on.
你从他的左右发起进攻
You attack at a 90-degree angle.
他要是朝向了你
When he turns to fight you,
我就逮到他的弱处了
leaves himself vulnerable to me.
等他跟我打的时候
When he turns to fight me--
就我上  一点没错
I get him. Exactly how it should be.
你怎么找到这里的  闪电侠
How'd you find this place, Flash?
我今天非揍扁你不可
I'm so gonna kick your ass.
又多出来一个
There's two of you now?
好吧  我是该害怕吗
Okay. Is that supposed to scare me?
害怕也是正常的
A little quaking in your boots wouldn't be inappropriate.
我就让你看看我有多害怕
Well, here's how scared I am of you.
我叫爱德华·克拉里斯
My name is Edward Clariss.
竞争者应该知道对方的名字
Rivals should know each other's names.
你们也应该告诉我的
I mean, you might as well tell me,
因为你们今晚不能活着离开这
since neither of you are leaving this place alive.
你又是谁
Who are you?
我吗
Me?
我是闪电侠
I'm the Flash.
你知道这个就够了
That's all you need to know.
等我从你的尸体上摘下面罩
Well, after I rip that cowl off your corpse,
也就知道你的身份了
I'll know who you are.
不过又是一个
Just another pretender
自以为能赢我的冒牌货
who thought they could take me on.
所以谁先来接神速力一招
So who wants to meet the Speed Force first?
各就各位
Hey, stay in position.
我能解决他
I can take him.
放心
I got this.
闪电侠正在普雷斯科特锯木厂对决竞争者
The Flash is taking on the Rival at Prescott Sawmill.
带人过去  不要让他们的
Get down there, make sure the action
战斗影响周边地区
doesn't spill out into the neighborhood.
我们不能让闪电侠孤军奋战
We can't leave the Flash out there alone.
沃利
Wally!
战袍遥感数据显示他还活着
Telemetry from the suit says he's still alive.
奄奄一息
Barely.
你不会有事的  好吗
You're going to be okay, all right?
你不会有事的  我救你出去
You're gonna be okay. I'm gonna get you out of here.
他从来就不是我的对手
That one was never my rival.
你倒是有点可能  想试试看吗
You could be, though. You want to find out?
打败我
Defeat me,
我就让你救你朋友
and I'll let you take your little friend for help.
不
No.
需要被救的是你
You're the one who's gonna need help.
再见了  闪电侠
Good-bye, Flash.
天哪
Oh, my God.
简直像《龙卷风》
It's like "Twister" in there,
是电影  不是游戏
the movie, not the game.
卫星检测到两种不同的漏斗形态
The satellite's picking up two distinct funnel patterns.
风暴级别F3[树木被连根拔起]
Tornados measure at F3 on the Fujita scale.
他简直能掌控天气
This guy's like a Weather Wizard or something.
各位
Guys!
我无法阻止他
I can't stop him.
听我说  巴里
Listen to me, Barry.
你说那个世界里我们是相爱的
You said we love each other in that other life.
如果我是那个世界的爱瑞丝
If I were your Iris from over there,
我相信我一定知道现在应该说什么
I'm sure I would know exactly what to say,
但我不是
but I don't.
我现在只能说  我相信你
All I can say is I believe in you.
你一定能阻止他
And you can stop this guy.
做闪电侠  巴里
Be the Flash, Barry.
因为那才是你
Because that's who you are.
你是闪电侠
You're the Flash.
我是闪电侠
I'm the Flash.
不可能
That's impossible.
你真的是世上速度最快的人
You really are the fastest man alive.
结束了
It's over.
乔
Joe.
是沃利  他需要帮助
It's Wally. He needs help.
沃利
Wally?
儿子
Son!
儿子  听到我说话吗
Son, can you hear me?
沃利的生命体征很弱  而且失血过多
Wally's vitals are low, and he's lost a lot of blood.
他应该能很快治愈
He should be rapidly healing.
这是极速者的天赋之一
It's one of the gifts of being a speedster.
他不能  我很抱歉
He's not. I'm sorry.
我可以走了吗
Am I free to go?
所以我才不要参与其中
This is why I didn't want to get involved.
打击犯罪真糟心
Crime fighting sucks.
我以为我能让事情变得更好
I thought I could just make things better,
却造成所有人为我的幸福牺牲
but everybody's been paying for my happiness.
你可以帮我吗
Will you help me?
帮你什么
Do what?
让事情回到正轨
Make things right.
我需要这个
I need that.
你不需要这个
You don't need that.
You do not need that.
大家好
Hey, guys.
小拳王
Hey, slugger.
这位是
Who's this?
她叫爱瑞丝
This is Iris.
很高兴见到你  爱瑞丝
It's nice to meet you, Iris.
你要喝点什么吗
Can I get you something to drink?
不用了  谢谢您  艾伦夫人
Oh, no, I'm okay. Thanks, Mrs. Allen.
你没事吧  巴里
You okay, Barry?
没事  我只是想
Yeah, I just...
再跟你们见一面
wanted to see you both one more time.
你这么说什么意思
What does...that mean?
没什么
Nothing.
没什么  我...
Nothing. I, uh...
过去三个月是最棒的日子
These last three months have been the best.
能跟你们一起度过
Just getting to spend time with you.
我只想让你们知道我很感激你们
I just...wanted you to know how grateful I am,
让我当你们的儿子
to both of you, to be your son.
巴里  你吓到我了
Barry, you're scaring me.
不  没什么好害怕的
No, there's-- there's nothing to be afraid of.
我保证
Promise.
我只是...
I just...
很爱你们
I love you both.
巴里
Hey, Barry!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
越来越糟了
It's getting worse.
我们要赶快  否则就来不及了
We have to hurry before it's too late.
今天过得不好啊  巴里
Having a bad day, Barr?
这可不是未来的艾伦夫人
Well...if it isn't the future Mrs. Allen.
巴里告诉我不要听你说的任何话
Barry told me not to listen to anything you say.
这不是好的忠告
That's just bad advice.
因为我是应答者
'Cause I'm the answer man.
我有求必应
I am the answer to all your prayers.
你只需要求我  巴里
All you need to do is ask me, Barry.
我们要回到那一年
We need to go back in time.
那一晚
To that night.
做什么
To do what?
你知道我要你做什么
You know what I need you to do.
但我想听你亲口说
But I want to hear you say it.
我要你杀我母亲
I need you to kill my mother.
乐意之至
With pleasure.
我恨你
I hate you.
我也恨你
And I hate you.
有时我在想到底我们谁对谁错
And I sometimes wonder which of us is right.
如果我说祝你好运挺怪的
It seems weird to wish you good luck.
我为这一切感到非常抱歉
I'm so sorry about all this.
我会知道什么时候恢复原样吗
Will I know when things change back?
我会有感觉吗
Will I feel it?
就像完全没发生过一样
It'll be like it never happened.
我们很快会再见面
I'll see you soon.
-巴里  -退后
- Barry! - Get back!
天呐  我真想杀了你
God, I wish I could kill you.
但今天
But today...
我要当英雄
I get to be the hero.
不
No!
这次你不能杀她
You're not gonna kill her this time.
你再也不能杀她
You're not gonna kill her ever again.
没事的
It's okay.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
好吗
Okay?
你安全了
You're safe.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
事实上
Actually...
她并不安全
she's not.
请不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
好了
There we go.
事情恢复原样了
Things are back to how they should be.
反正对我而言是
Well, for me, anyway.
对你而言
For you...
就...
Well...
只能等你去探索了
I guess you'll just have to wait and find out.
什么  你在说什么
What? What does that mean?
我们很快再见  闪电侠
See you sometime soon, Flash.
为什么抱我
What's this for?
只是很高兴见到你
Just glad you're here.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事  我现在没事
Yeah, I am now. Yeah.
你刚失去了父亲  巴里
You just lost your father, Barry.
你不用装作没事
You don't have to be okay.
事实上  我感觉我反而跟父母更亲近了
Actually, I feel closer to my parents than I ever have.
很好  孩子
Well, good, son.
-敬你的父亲们  -敬亨利
- To your pops. - To Henry.
敬我的爸爸
To my Dad.
爱瑞丝在哪里
Where's Iris?
这不好笑
That ain't funny.
我就当你是悲伤过度吧
I'm gonna chalk that up to grief.
明早再见你们
I'll see you both in the morning.
怎么了
What was that about?
你开我玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你知道爱瑞丝不在这里
You know Iris isn't here.
什么
What?
他们冷战了  巴里
They don't talk, Barry.
你知道的
You know that.
天呐  我做了什么
Oh, God. What did I do?
克拉里斯
Clariss.
Clariss!
是谁
Who's there?
是时候醒来了
It's time to wake up.
炼金术